ANTE BUDIMIR

62 Klokocevac, BJ, Croatia • <u>developer@antebudimir.com</u> • <u>www.antebudimir.com</u> • +385996951148 • skype: abudimir85

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

<div id="root">Enthusiastic developer with 2 years of experience freelancing in Kazakhstan and Croatia. Focused on designs that are mobile-first, functional and user friendly above all. function vanilla(JS), PWA's and accessibility in design. const learning = ['React', 'Typescript']. Extensive client management skills gained on multibillion-dollar international oil & gas projects in Russia and Kazakhstan. Synthesizer player and all things tech while not coding. Fluent in Croatian, English and Russian.

KEY SKILLS

- Semantic HTML
- CSS / SASS
- Mobile-first design

- JavaScript
- API implementation
- Progressive Web Apps
- GIT version control
- Communication
- Multilingual

EXPERIENCE

Freelancer, (Kazakhstan & Croatia)

2019 - 2021

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

- Developed custom websites from scratch using modern CSS techniques, with cross-browser compatibility and accessibility in mind.
- Wrote semantic HTML5, validated it, and paid attention to the best SEO practices.
- Implemented mobile-first approach to existing websites and often decreased loading times by 20-30%.
- Consumed API's using modern asynchronous JavaScript with Async and Await.
- Developed and marketed Progressive Web Apps, as a cheaper way for clients to get a native-like app.
- Wrote and optimized JavaScript to develop attractive user interfaces.
- Used Chrome DevTools for inspecting code, debugging |S and measuring performance with Lighthouse.
- Implemented recommendations from Lighthouse and learned from them.
- Used GIT and GitHub for version control and backup of my code.
- Used linters such as Prettier and ESLint to make sure my code is well formatted and readable.
- Used SASS to componentize my CSS and make it as reusable as possible.
- Collaborated with designers to make functional and attractive user interfaces and great user experience.
- Communicated directly with clients, and always found a satisfactory solution for everyone involved.

OOO "Velesstroy", "3GI", Chevron project, Tengiz (Kazakhstan)

2017 - 2019

HSE COMPLIANCE LEAD

- Supervised the construction of access roads and Chevron's camp facilities that inhabits 2000 people.
- Negotiated terms with local providers of safety trainings as well as medical and emergency services.
- Served as a liaison between Velesstroy and 8 of its subcontractors and managed HSE compliance issues.
- Chaired safety meetings and made reports and presentations on HSE results to the board of directors.

HSE OFFICER AND TRAINER

- Supervised a team of 4 HSE officers and coordinated their site activities.
- Facilitated incident investigations and ensured relevant information for insurance purposes.
- Achieved 10 million consecutive man-hours with zero recordable incidents.
- Conducted HSE awareness campaigns in the form of presentations and safety talks.

Protecta Horvat d.o.o. Bjelovar (Croatia)

2012 - 2015

PRIVATE SECURITY CEO

- Negotiated terms of contracts and closed deals with government and private entities.
- Ensured that all deals meet the required revenue and growth expectations.
- Conducted periodical performance evaluation of staff with the aim of increasing employee efficiency.
- Made projections, analysed business results and presented reports to the stockholders.

Prima commerce d.o.o. Bjelovar (Croatia)

2011 - 2012

HSE MANAGER

- Developed HSE department budget and assured expenditures did not exceed the limit.
- Enhanced individual safety compliance through training and safety rewards programme.
- Disseminated and implemented various learning points arrived from accidents.
- Developed and implemented waste management system for oil, car batteries, tires and scrap wood.

EDUCATION & CONTINUING DEVELOPMENT COURSEWORK

NEBOSH National General Certificate in Occupational Health and Safety, Glasgow (Scotland), 2017

HSE SPECIALIST, Industrial Safety and Capital Construction Academy, Moscow (Russia), 2016

LICENSED HSE Engineer, National Safety Certificate, Ministry of Labour and Social Welfare, Croatia, 2012

HSE ENGINEER, College for Occupational Safety and Health, Zagreb (Croatia), 2010 (Masters at NFQ Level 9)

COMPUTER SKILLS

Advanced user of the following operating systems and programs:

- Windows OS XP, 7, 10
- Linux Ubuntu OS
- MS Office (Word, Excel, Powerpoint, Outlook)
- VS Code

- Adobe Audition
- Adobe Photoshop
- CyberLink Power Director
- FL Studio 20

LANGUAGE SKILLS

- Croatian native
- Serbian near native

- English fluent
- Russian fluent

PERSONAL INFO

 LinkedIn profile: www.linkedin.com/in/ante-budimir

- Eligible to work in the EU
- Driving License: Croatian and International (B)

• • •